Okay. So, the next thing I'm going to
show you is how you can create your own
branch. What a branch is is it looks at
the code, takes a copy, and then you can
work on that copy, and then when you
decide to, you can eventually bring that
copy back and merge it with the original
code and keep the changes that you want
from the copy and not keep some of the
changes you don't want. Sometimes you'll
even make a copy and then you'll decide,
"Oh, that was a useless pursuit." And
you'll just delete the copy. Um, but
your main code stays safe from any
accidental changes. Um, so you basically
never ever ever want to be developing on
the main copy of your code. If anyone
tells you differently,
ask them how long they've been coding.
Um, because if they've been coding for a
while, they probably will not tell you
that. Um, so what you want to do is you
want to come to your current branch and
you can click this dropown and it'll say
currently you are on the main version of
the code. We do not want to edit the
main version of the code because that
could lead to huge problems. So, we're
going to do is we're going to click this
new branch button. And then we're going
to create a branch. Usually, you want to
name your branch something descriptive.
Um, probably the feature that you're
working on for the app. So, in my case,
this is the very first thing I'm
creating, but I'm going to create a
multiply function. So, I like to put my
name in front of it and then multiply
function. So, I've got my name and then
I've got this description of what I'm
doing for this project. And then I'm
going to hit create branch.
You will know you're successful if the
current branch switches from saying main
up here to saying your branch. So, um if
you want to switch branches, you can
click on main. Now, we are on the main
version of our code, the version we do
not want to be editing. Um, over here we
are on a perfect duplicate of that main
branch. And now we can edit the code
here, run tests here, make sure
everything works here. And then once
we're sure that it works, we can put it
back into the other one. So, um, I'm
going to open this up in Visual Studio
Code and I'm going to add a file and I'm
going to call this multiply.js.
And I'm going to write a function here,
const multiply.
And I'm going to use the arrow function
syntax.
And I'm going to accept A and B.
And then I'm going to return A* B. And
I'll save that. And then in the next
video I'll talk you about talk to you
about how you can save those changes to
your repository.